

MD. MONIR HOSSAN

Address: Babu's House, Boodhua Para, Bashundhara Gate, Dhaka 1212.

Email: <u>mdraju01820@gmail.com</u> **Contact**: +8801701050966

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/md-monir-hossan-283290199

GitHub: https://github.com/MDMONIRHOSSAN

Profile

I am a self-driven, motivated and passionate individual with 1+ year of experience in software engineering field looking for a Software Engineer position where I can prove my technical, analytical, interpersonal and leadership skills and knowledge.

Key Skills

<u>Advance</u>: Python, Django, Django Rest Framework, Rasa, GitHub, Slack, Trello.

<u>Intermediate</u>: Flask, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery, JavaScript, Java, Heroku, Bit bucket, SQLAlchemy, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

<u>Primary:</u> Docker, MongoDB (Atlas), Angular, Web Scraping, PHP, Swift, Swift UI, Selenium, Machine Learning, Neural Network.

Academic Projects

Senior Design Project

(https://deploy-rbc-test.herokuapp.com/)

Cost and Time efficient Computer Aided Commercial Software for Blood Pathogens.

A web application which resides an Al Base Visual Recognition System.

Implemented in Flask framework.

Design Rest API for Mobile Application.

Internet and Web Technology (https://online-travel-tours.000webhostapp.com/)

Online Travel and Tour Agency using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 4, JS, jQuery, PHP

Software Quality Assurances & Testing

Generate HTML format Resume using Java & JavaFX as well as Unit Testing.

Black box testing of a website using Selenium framework in Java.

Programming Language II (JAVA)

Medical Management System using Java & Swing.

Leadership/Other Skills

Former Sub-Executive in NSU ACM Student Chapter. In-Charge of TECNOVATION event in 2018. Lead all academic projects as team leader.

Education

North South University Dhaka (2015 - 2020)

Bachelor in Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) CGPA: **3.32**

Bangladesh Navy School & College, Chittagong (2014)

Higher Secondary School Certificate (Science)

GPA: 4.80

Experience

English Essence Ltd.

Software Engineer (October 2020 – Present)

Build entire backend system from scratch.

Design API for mobile application.

Design dashboard for teacher's and super admin.

Rokomari

Customer Chat Bot (Project Based)

Build contextual AI assistants that really help customers. Automate FAQ & customer care service partially.

cWork Microjob Limited

Jr. Software Engineer (March 2020 - June 2020)

Maintain backend service developed on DRF Integrate backend server into Chatbot via API. Maintain frontend application developed on Angular.

YODA

Web Designer & IOS Intern (November 2018 – August 2019)

Design IOS mobile application using swift.

Integrate backend server API in IOS application.

Deign modern web pages using HTML, CSS & Bootstrap.

Personal Projects

Basa Khujchi (Beta Version)

A web application for home rental system of Bangladesh. Developed on Django framework.

Home Decorate

(https://online-store-5005-test.herokuapp.com/)

An online store web application for home decoration. Developed on Django framework.